Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over the process of adding our own custom enemy character.
In the last lecture, we made a Child Blueprint class, which inherits all the main components of our
skeleton enemy.
In this lecture, we'll make it so that this blueprint uses the animations of whatever enemy that you
want to set up.
So to get started, you want to create a new folder for the custom enemy that you want to use.
So I'm just going to go create a new folder and I'm going to call this folder goblin, because the enemy
that I'm going to add is going to be a goblin.
Then we just want to head inside this folder.
Okay, So I imported five animations for my new enemy, The animations that you need to make sure that
your enemy has is one animation of your enemy attacking an animation of your enemy dying, an animation
of your enemy in its idle animation, an animation of your enemy running and an animation of your enemy
taking damage.
Once you've got all those animations, create a new folder for each of them and then extract the animations
inside these images and create them into flip books.
So I'm just going to go through the process now.
It's the exact same thing that we did for the skeleton and the mushroom enemy.
Okay, so I created a folder for each of my animations and made a flipbook for each of the animations.
Once you've done that inside of your new enemy folder, just create a new folder and cool the split
books.
And make sure to put each animation folder inside of this folder just to keep things organized.
Then once you've done that right click and go new folder and just pull this animations.
Then if you hadn't saw it here, you want to right click and go Paper Z and select animation source
and just call this the Goblin or whatever your enemy is called animation source.
Then if we open it up, you want to go add new new animation sequence and cool this first one attack.
So this can be the animation of your enemy attacking.
So for me, it's called Goblin attack.
Then I'm going to add another one and I'm just going to call this one idle.
And this will be my goblin idol.
Then there was one for my enemy running.
So this one running.
And here I will select the goblin run.
Then now one for the enemy taking damage.
So I'll just call this take damage.
And here under animation, I will look for the goblin, take damage.
And then there's one for the enemy dying.
So I'll just go this die.
And here are the animation data.
I'll look for Goblin die.
So now we have all the animations for our Copeland enemy.
We can save this and close this.
Then if you just right click and go Paper CD and select paper.
CD Animation Blueprint.
We want to select the Goblin animation source and just call this the Goblin or whatever your enemy is
called Animation Blueprint.
Then if you actually go over to the scan folder and to the blueprints folder and just move this Miller
enemy underscore two to the goblin folder.
And just right click and create a new folder and just cool this blueprint.
And then I'm going to move this inside this folder.
And just right click and rename this the problem.
Enemy.
And then if you go over to the animation folder, open up the animation blueprint for the new enemy.
Then right click and look, forget owning actor.
And we just want to drag up here a look for cast for the Goblin Enemy or whatever.
You name the blueprint.
Benge was right click on its value, permit it to a variable and we can just call this all goblin reference.
And then if you go over to the animation graph, we want to right click and look for new state machine
and connect this into here.
So initially all of our the first thing we're going to do is create a new animation state.
And we can just call this our idle slash run state.
And if we head inside here, then if we just drag in our copying reference and what we want to do is
get the velocity of this.
From here, we can drag off and get the back to length.
And then if we just dry off and we want to check to see if its value is not equal to zero.
So if this value is not equal to zero, that means our goblin is moving.
And so we'll play the running animation.
If this is false, then we'll play the Goblin Auto animation.
So if you just right click and look for select animations by ball and hook this up here and animation
into here for the false animation, we just right click and look for play Idol and connect this into
here and for the tree animation we just want to right click and for play running and connect this into
here.
Then if we go back to the new state machine, we just want to right click and go create jump node and
just call this attack event.
And when we call the detachment, we are going to create a new animation state.
And this will be when the goblin is attacking.
So it's attacking.
And if we head inside here, we just want to play the attack animation for the goblin.
And if we go out of this.
If we create another jump node.
So I'm going to right click and go create jump node and let's just call this damaged.
Then if we drag from this jump node and go create new animation state and just call this take damage,
and if we head inside here, we want to right click and look for the.
Damage animations.
So select it.
Connect it in here.
And then if you connect from the take damage to the item slash run and head inside here and in order
to transition from our take damage back to our idle slash front animation, we're going to right click
and look for time remaining.
And we want this one time remaining of whatever your animation is called.
And when this is less than, let's say, 0.1, we will connect this into here and enter the animation.
Then if we right click again and go create jump node and call this death.
Then drag up here and go animation state and we can just call this the die.
And if we hit inside here, right click and look for Play Your Death animation.
So I called my play Die and Connect it into here.
And then one thing I realized that I didn't do with the other animations if we just let this play die
animation, we can just uncheck this loop animation.
That way, when it plays this animation, it's just going to end at the last frame of this animation
in the other animation blueprint that I made.
So for example, in the Skeleton one, I made it so we transition into this dead body animation.
But I realized we can just make sure that this is unchecked and then it will just leave it on the last
frame of the animation.
And then there's one more thing you want to do.
If you just close this and open up your goblin animation tools and go over to the TAC animation and
basically just before your enemy attacks.
Just so for me, it's around frame six, just right click and go add notify.
And we're going to go new notify and just call this attack.
And then if you go back to the Goblin animation blueprint, we should see the attack notify here and
then drag in the Goblin reference and forget Goblin reference.
I'm just going to close this and go back to my Goblin blueprint because its parent class is the skeleton
beep.
That basically means it will inherit all the blueprints inside of the scans and blueprint and inside
of the skeleton blueprint.
We call this a custom event which will do a line trace and try and damage anything which is hit by this
line trace inside of our goblin.
Whenever it reaches this animation, we are going to reference that custom event inside of the skeleton
blueprint.
And because this is a chart of the scans and blueprint, we can reference all the nodes and custom events
inside this phantom blueprint.
So over here, drag off and look for attack.
And this will call the attack inside of the Scantron beep.
And we can just connect this here and then go compile.
Then there's one final thing we need to do, and that is set up the common enemy.
So if I just open it up and just select the sprite, the first thing I'm going to do is change this
to be the goblin item.
And I'm actually just going to move this capsule radius that kind of fits the goblin a bit better.
Okay, next I'm going to scroll down and select the animation component, and we just want to select
the Goblin animation blueprint that we just made.
And then if you go over to the enemy itself.
We want to just close this.
We want to go over to the edit section and you'll see three nodes damage, jump node, death, jump
node and attack jump node.
And if you go back to your enemy animation blueprint, you basically want to get the name or whatever
you call these jump nodes and make sure that they align with these.
So for the damage jump node, whenever my goblin enters its damaged animation, we call this damage
drop node.
So make sure this is spelt correctly and has the same value here.
So I don't need to change that for the death one in this.
I just called it death as well and put the attack event.
Yeah, I just call that attack event so I don't need to change any of these.
But let's say you name this like.
Dying then here under a Trump node, make sure that's spelt correctly.
Okay, so now we can test out this new enemy.
Let's just go compile save close this.
Then if I drag in my goblin enemy, I'm going to move them to layer 20, because that's the layer that
I'm currently on.
And let's just go play.
My goblin will do its normal walking animation.
You said jump in front of it.
It should recognize me and then start attacking me.
I can attack it.
So attack it.
And then I'll do its damage animation.
And let's say I kill it.
Then the goblin will die and play death animation.
And with that, we have set up a new enemy.
So you could basically do that process to add more enemies.
And it would be the exact same process to add arranged enemy.